<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security Summer School – Contribution guidelines</title><link>/docs/contribution-guidelines/</link><description>Recent content in Contribution guidelines on Security Summer School</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/docs/contribution-guidelines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Contributor guidelines</title><link>/docs/contribution-guidelines/contributor-guideline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/contribution-guidelines/contributor-guideline/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="first-step">First Step&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Some good first steps and best practices when using Git are explained here:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the Git Immersion tutorial: &lt;a href="https://gitimmersion.com/">https://gitimmersion.com/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the Atlassian tutorial: &lt;a href="https://www.atlassian.com/git/tutorials/learn-git-with-bitbucket-cloud">https://www.atlassian.com/git/tutorials/learn-git-with-bitbucket-cloud&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>this blog post on the ROSEdu Techblog: &lt;a href="https://techblog.rosedu.org/git-good-practices.html">https://techblog.rosedu.org/git-good-practices.html&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="language">Language&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>All of our content is developed in English.
This means we use English for content, support code, commit messages, pull requests, issues, comments, everything.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="content-writing-style">Content Writing Style&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This section addresses the development of session content and other Markdown files.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Write each sentence on a new line. This way, changing one sentence only affects one line in the source code.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use the &lt;strong>first person plural&lt;/strong> when writing documentation and tutorials.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use phrases like &lt;code>we run the command / app&lt;/code>, &lt;code>we look at the source code&lt;/code>, &lt;code>we find the flag&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use the second person for challenges and other individual activities.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use phrases like &lt;code>find the flag&lt;/code>, &lt;code>run this command&lt;/code>, &lt;code>download the tool&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="issues">Issues&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When opening an issue, please clearly state the problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Make sure it&amp;rsquo;s reproducible.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add images if required.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Also, if relevant, detail the environment you used (OS, software versions).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ideally, if the issue is something you could fix, open a pull request with the fix.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="discussions">Discussions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Use Github discussions for bringing up ideas on content, new chapters, new sections.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Provide support to others asking questions and take part in suggestions brought by others.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For in-depth discussions, please join the &lt;a href="https://bit.ly/DiscordSecuritySummerSchool">SSS Discord community&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Please be civil when taking part in discussions.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="pull-requests">Pull Requests&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For pull requests, please follow the &lt;a href="https://docs.github.com/en/github/collaborating-with-pull-requests/proposing-changes-to-your-work-with-pull-requests/creating-a-pull-request-from-a-fork">GitHub flow&lt;/a>: create a fork of the repository, create your own branch, do commits, push changes to your branch, do a pull request (PR).&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The destination branch of pull requests is the default &lt;code>master&lt;/code> branch.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make sure each commit corresponds to &lt;strong>one&lt;/strong> code / content change only.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Also make sure one pull request covers only &lt;strong>one&lt;/strong> topic.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How a good commit message should look like: &lt;a href="https://cbea.ms/git-commit/">https://cbea.ms/git-commit/&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The use of &lt;code>-s&lt;/code> / &lt;code>--signoff&lt;/code> when creating a commit is optional, but strongly recommended.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Reviewer guidelines</title><link>/docs/contribution-guidelines/reviewer-guideline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/contribution-guidelines/reviewer-guideline/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="activities--challenges">Activities / Challenges&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Make sure that activities / challenges are of good quality:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Difficulty is properly set.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The topic of the activity / challenge is appropriate.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The provided solution is working.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Vulnerability and explanations are easy to understand.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="assets">Assets&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Check if all of them are used and mentioned in the content.
If the assets are not original, make sure their license is compatible to &lt;a href="https://github.com/security-summer-school/template-public/blob/master/COPYING.md">ours&lt;/a> and that their source is properly cited.
Verify that their names are appropriate and respect the following rules:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Use dash between words (e.g. &lt;code>image-name.png&lt;/code>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use only lowercase ASCII characters.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="content">Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Make sure that the content is of good quality:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>It follows the general structure of a &lt;a href="https://github.com/security-summer-school/template-public/blob/master/session-name-1/README.md">session&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Assets are displayed well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The content has at most one sentence per line.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The content is easy to understand.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wording and general spelling are correct.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Proper formatting is used (such as bold, italic, typewriter formats).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="working-on-pull-requests">Working on Pull Requests&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You will review contributions as pull requests, following the &lt;a href="https://docs.github.com/en/pull-requests/collaborating-with-pull-requests/reviewing-changes-in-pull-requests/about-pull-request-reviews">PR review guidelines from GitHub&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add your review as comments and request for changes to the PR until everything is ready to be approved.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add any comments regarding one or more explicit lines as review comments and only publish them together when submitting your review.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Do not add each individual suggestion or comment as standalone.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Before approving the PR, make sure that all Github Actions tests ended successfully.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once approved, either you or someone with proper access rights can use &lt;code>Rebase and merge&lt;/code> to merge the PR commits and integrate the contribution.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>